fanack.com 2019-05-20

# Fanack Privacy Statement - Fanack.com

__October 31st, 2011 / September 5th, 2018

 **In this notice, we explain how we handle any personal data that we obtain through our web sites or when you contact us by mail or phone. Our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect and use the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Fanack web sites.**

### Summary

Fanack sometimes collects personal information, but we never use it for marketing purposes. You won’t receive any spam if you leave your email address anywhere on our web sites. We are committed to a lawful, fair and transparent processing of personal data, adhering to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). When you sign-up for our newsletter you consent to us using your personal data in the way that we describe here. This also includes the placing of cookies as explained below.

Fanack respects your privacy and collects no personally identifiable information about you unless you affirmatively choose to make such information available to us. Fanack does not actively share personal information about web site visitors.

Personal information provided by visitors, such as e-mail addresses or information submitted via online forms, is used by Fanack to assist individual visitors as necessary. This assistance may involve redirecting an inquiry or comment to another Fanack individual or unit better suited to provide resolution.

Fanack analyses its webserver log files to collect summary information about visitors to its web sites. Fanack also subscribes to Google Analytics, which uses cookies to collect anonymous traffic data. This information is analysed by Fanack and by Google Analytics to generate summary statistics for purposes such as guiding design considerations, determining successful sitessegments, and determining problem areas.

Fanack is a research and content sharing foundation. At anytime there are numerous online surveys being conducted on Fanack web sites.

Confidential information gathered in these online surveys is used only for the research purpose indicated in the survey. Unless otherwise noted on the specified survey, your answers are confidential and individual responses will not be shared with other parties unless required by law. Aggregate data from surveys may be shared with external third parties.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on a Fanack web sites we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to a Fanack web site, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to a Fanack web sitescan download and extract any location data from images on the web sites.

### Information you provide to us

We collect the following information when you use our web sites, contact us, or sign up for our newsletter. When you contact us by mail, phone or through the contact form or chat on our web sites: we collect your name, email address or phone number, and any other information you may provide to us. When you sign up for our newsletter: we collect your name and email address.

 **We use this information:**

To reply to your information request when you contacted us or have a customer question.  
For our own marketing communication correspondence, most importantly our newsletter.

 **We store:**

  * Customer support information for up to a year.
  * Marketing information for up to five years.

We process this data based on your consent. In case of customer support we need the information to be able to provide you that service although It is not a contractual or statutory requirement to provide this information.

### Information we obtain about you

Mailchimp, our newsletter service provider, tracks how you engage with the newsletter, including opens and links clicks. We will use this information to make a better newsletter.

We also use Google Analytics and in the way described below.

### Cookies

Similar to other Web sites, our web sites utilizes a standard technology called “cookies” (see explanation below, “What Are Cookies?”) and Web server logs to collect information about how our Web sitesis used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Web sites.

Fanack, our advertisers and ad serving companies may also use small pieces of code called “web beacons” or “clear gifs” to determine which advertisements and promotions users have seen and how users responded to them.

If you leave a comment on our sitesyou may opt-in to saving your name, email address and web sitesin cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

We use the following cookies:

Name| How Long| Placed By| Reason  
---|---|---|---  
_gat| 1 minute| Google Inc.| We use Google Analytics. This is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. to count visitors to our web sites and analyse their usage of the sitesto help us determine the value of our content to our users. [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).  
_ga| 2 years from set/update| Google Inc.| We use Google Analytics. This is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. to count visitors to our web sites and analyse their usage of the sitesto help us determine the value of our content to our users. [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).  
  
Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service, we use <https://akismet.com/>, see their privacy policy at <https://automattic.com/privacy/>

### Embedded content from other web sites

Articles on this sitesmay include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other web sites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other web sites.

These web sites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that web sites.

## Sharing information

We sometimes share your personal data with other companies. This includes outside service providers that we use for processing your data, for example:

  * Companies that support us in sending emails and other messages related to our marketing. This is currently Mailchimp, operated by The Rocket Science Group LLC. Read their privacy policy here: <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>.
  * Companies that provide our web siteshosting. This is currently Savvii Read more about how they handle data here: <https://www.savvii.nl/privacyverklaring/>.

We require these companies to adequately safeguard your personal data and not use your data for any other purpose not authorized by us.

We might sell (part of) our business to another company. Such transfer of ownership could include the transfer of your personal data to the buyer if the data directly relates to that (part of the) business.

We will also release personal data to the authorities, if we are compelled to do so by law.

We will not sell or provide your personal data to other third parties allowing them to use your personal data for their own purposes.

You should also know that your personal data may be transferred from your home country to our service providers. If you are an EU resident, this could imply that we also transfer data to countries or organizations that do not offer a so-called adequate level of protection for your personal data.

When we transfer this data, we will do so only when we have put in place appropriate safeguards to protect your personal data. Please contact us to obtain a copy of the safeguards that we have put in place. Our contact details can be found at the bottom.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our web sites(if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). web sitesadministrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

You have the right to request from us access to your personal data that we process. You also have the right to:  
– Rectify incorrect personal data or erase it in certain circumstances.  
– Restrict or object to the processing of your personal data.  
– Receive your data so that you can use it elsewhere (data portability).

You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please be aware that a withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of the processing of your data before the date on which you withdrew your consent.

Finally, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority. If you do not know who your supervisory authority is, please contact us and we will tell you.

## Contact Us

You can contact us with any questions you may have about the processing of your personal data or the use of cookies by us, or to exercise the above rights, at: [Fanack](https://fanack.com/contact/).

## We would like to ask you something …

Fanack is an independent media organisation, not funded by any state or any interest group, that distributes in the Middle East and the wider world unbiased analysis and background information, based on facts, about the Middle East and North Africa.

The website grew rapidly in breadth and depth and today forms a rich and valuable source of information on 21 countries, from Morocco to Oman and from Iran to Yemen, both in Arabic and English. We currently reach six million readers annually and growing fast.

In order to guarantee the impartiality of information on the Chronicle, articles are published without by-lines. This also allows correspondents to write more freely about sensitive or controversial issues in their country. All articles are fact-checked before publication to ensure that content is accurate, current and unbiased.

### To run such a website is very expensive. With a small donation, you can make a huge impact. And it only takes a minute. Thank you.
